CLANCY ROSE: The next thing I'm going to talk about is mixing the milk for the breve and then steaming the milk.
So today I am going to be making breve because I don't actually have a pitcher of Half & Half and that's all the breve is.
So if you have Half & Half then you just use that.
To make breve, I am going to use half whole milk and half heavy whipping cream, and I'm going to pour it into my pitcher and I'm going to be doing this in a 14-ounce cup, so that means I'm going to fill out the milk into the pitcher right up to this ridge and that's about how milk you should use in your pitcher.
And I'm going to move on to steaming the milk.
So I'm going to do this in three motions.
First, position the pitcher around the steam wand in such a way that when you turn on the steam wand the milk starts to swirl inside the pitcher around the edges of the pitcher.
You do that until you can feel the milk temperature kind of match your hand and it's right about 100 degrees.
You feel that warm break in the milk.
All right, when that happens you're going to lower the pitcher down to where the tip of the steam wand is right above the surface of the milk.
You're going to hear air starting to be introduced into the milk, and what you're doing in that process is creating the foam for the drink.
You're going to do that for a little bit longer than you would if you are using normal milk.
So in this drink, we're going to do it about seven or eight seconds, and then after you stretch the milk then you raise the pitcher back up so that the steam wand is submerged down into the milk and get the position right again so that it swirls and keep it swirling until it's at the temperature that you want to drink.